suu.edu 2019-04-01

# Privacy Statement | SUU

Southern Utah University has created this statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. This document explains how we gather, use, and protect your information.

## We Don't Sell Your Contact Information 

While using this site, you may choose to submit personal information through email or online forms. We will use this information to process your requests. We will not intentionally sell, share, or distribute your personal information to third parties, except as required by law or University policy.

## Statistical Logs Kept 

SUU uses programs to collect data about visitor traffic to our site. We do not attempt to personally identify visitors. Instead we collect data to analyze in aggregate to determine trends and improve our sites. Here are some examples of the types of data we routinely collect:

  * Internet address of computer
  * Browser type
  * Device type
  * Referring web page
  * Date, time & duration of visit
  * Cookies Used to Preserve Data
  * Internal search terms

## Cookies

Most websites use cookies. A cookie is a small text file that a website saves on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences (such as login, language, display preferences) either during a single session or over a period of time, so you don't have to keep re-entering information during a session or whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to another. For instance, the mySUU portal uses cookies (active only during your session) to remember password and menu settings. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can turn them off in your browser or set your browser to ask you before accepting new cookies although this may affect functionality. Cookie information is not used to identify you personally.

## Security Programs Running 

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, to assist in maintaining data security, and to assist in correctly using the information we collect online. We do not intentionally release personal information gleaned from these programs to others, except as required by law.

## Security Precautions You Should Take  

Although we make every effort to secure our networks, the University cannot guarantee privacy of online communications. Use discretion in providing information in online classes, chatrooms, or other open forums on the Web. If you use mySUU to access personal records, be sure to "lock up" when you leave by exiting the site AND closing your browser. Otherwise, the next person to use the computer may see your information. 

## Alternate Ways to Submit Information 

You have a choice about whether to provide personal information online. For other options, contact the department associated with the form being completed to learn how you can provide information by phone, mail, fax or in person.

## Other Sites Have Different Policies 

This site contains links to other independently managed sites. Some may use information for purposes other than stated above; be sure to read their separate privacy statements. University sites also contain links to sites outside SUU; these sites may have their own privacy statement -- or none at all. We urge you to exercise caution when providing personal data to any site. Check their policies and contact them if you have questions. 

## Protecting Children's Privacy 

We encourage parents to explore our website with their children. If we learn that a child under age 13 has provided personally identifiable information to our sites, we will promptly remove this from our files. For more on children's privacy rights, read about the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/rules/rulemaking-regulatory-reform-proceedings/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule) at the FTC's website.

## Changing Your Information 

Here's how to review or change your personal profile information (address, home phone, e-mail):

On the Web – Log into [mySUU](https://my.suu.edu/) and visit your profile

In Person – Visit the Registrar’s Office in the Sharwan Smith Center or the Alumni Office
